Western Federation of Miners International Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers Records 5268
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- American Civil Liberties Union, Publication (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: The Victory in New Jersey: The Decision of the Highest Court Reversing the Conviction of Roger S. Baldwin and Others for Unlawful Assembly in the Paterson Silk Strike of 1924, 1928; Publication (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Notes: June, 1928. 20 pp.
  - Item 6: Let Freedom Ring, Publication (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Author: Arthur Garfield Hays
  - Item 7: Announcing "Let Freedom Ring" by Arthur Garfield Hays, Publication (Box 5, Folder 2)
- The Northwest Organizer (Two Issues), 1938; Publication (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: The Northwest Organizer, 1938; Publication (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Author: Minneapolis Teamsters Joint Council
    Notes: v.4:no.2 (1938:Apr. 28)
  - Item 2: The Northwest Organizer, 1938; Publication (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Notes: v.4:no.4 (1938:May 12)
- The Plebs (Two Issues), 1926; Publication (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: The Plebs, 10926; Publication (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Author: National Council of Labour Colleges
    Notes: v.18:no.5 (1926:May)
  - Item 2: The Plebs, 1926; Publication (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.18:no.6 (1926:June). Strike Issue
- Government Publications, Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: For The Release of Political Prisoners: Speeches of Hon. George Huddleston of Alabama in the House of Representatives, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Author: George Huddleson
    Notes: December 11 and 14, 1922. 13 pp.
  - Item 2: Report of Federal Trade Commission Regarding Profiteering, 1918; Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Author: William B. Colver; John Franklin Fort; Victor Murdock
    Notes: Document no.248. Letter from the chairman of the Federal Trade Commission in response to a Senate resolution of June 10, 1918, transmitting a report containing all facts, figures, data, or information now in possession of the Federal Trade Commission rela
  - Item 3: Senator From Wisconsin: Report from the Committee on privileges and Elections, 1918; Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Author: William P. Dillingham
    Notes: Calendar no.560. Report No. 614. December 2, 1918. 50 pp.
  - Item 4: The North Dakota Industrial Program, 1920; Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Author: The Industrial Commission of North Dakota
    Notes: May 1, 1920. 86 pp.
  - Item 5: Public Meeting: Speakers Stephen Fry and A. G. Waite, 1920; Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Author: "Wheeler for Governor" Club
    Notes: Broadside.
- Industrial Workers of the World - Broadsides, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: The Only Real Agitator is Injustice, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Author: California District Defense Committee
    Notes: 4 pp.
  - Item 2: American Workers! What Are You Going to Do About It? Shall American Troops Be Used to Police Europe in the Interest of the Capitalist Class?, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Do You Want Mob Rule?, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: Do You Want Mob Rule?, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Notes: 4 pp. Copy 2.
  - Item 5: A Message From the City Jail of Centralia, Wash.: Has Patriotism in Cantralia Become the Last Refuge of Centralia's Scoundrels?, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 6: A Message From Five Jailed Workers In The Lewis County Jail. (Washington) - Jailed Because They tried to Organize the Workers. - Why Jail Men for Their Opinions?, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 7: To All Metal Mine Workers: The I.W.W. Is Coming: Join The One Big Union, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Author: Metal Mine Workers Industrial Union
  - Item 8: To All Metal Mine Workers: The I.W.W. Is Coming: Join The One Big Union, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 9: Workers, Judge For Yourselves About Centralia!, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Author: Northwest District Defense Committee
  - Item 10: Cut Down The Hours of Work!, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 11: Go Slow! "At the Devil's booth are all things sold, Each ounce of dross costs its ounce of gold.", Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 12: Go Slow! "At the Devil's booth are all things sold, Each ounce of dross costs its ounce of gold.", Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 13: Three Kinds of Strikes, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Author: Lumber Workers' Industrial Union, No. 120. IWW.
    Notes: 4 pp. Copy 3.
  - Item 14: Three Kinds of Strikes, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 15: Destroying the Home, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Notes: 2 pp.
  - Item 16: Destroying the Home, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Notes: 2 pp. Copy 2.
  - Item 17: Does the I.W.W, Preach Violence!, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 18: Does the I.W.W, Preach Violence!, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 19: Lumber Workers Organize!, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 20: Lumber Workers Organize!, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 21: Mr. Daugherty is Mistaken! There are Political Prisoners in the United States - 114 of them - despite the Attorney General's Statements to the Contrary, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Author: General Defense Commiittee
  - Item 22: Railroad Development Shows Seed for New Unionism, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Author: Railroad Workers Industrial Union No. 520
  - Item 23: To The Miners And All Men Working In And Around The Mines Of Butte, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Author: Butte Branch, Metal Mine Workers Industrial Union Local 800
    Notes: 1 pp.
  - Item 24: To The Miners And All Men Working In And Around The Mines Of Butte, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Notes: 1 pp. Copy 2.
  - Item 25: In Memory of Frank Little, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Author: J. J. Ferris
    Notes: Song. 1p.
  - Item 26: In Memory of Fellow Worker Frank Little, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Author: Joe Kennedy
  - Item 27: A Fair Trial? A Record of the Prejudice and Passion that Dominated the Legal Profession and the Press in the Famous Centralia Labor Case, 1920; Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Author: Frank Walklin
    Notes: Tried at Montesano, Washington, Jan. 26th - March 15th, 1920. 15 pp.
- Industrial Workers of the World Publications 1, Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Justice and the I.W.W., Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Author: Paul F. Brissenden
    Notes: n.d. 31 pp.
  - Item 2: Hotel Restaurant and Domestic Workers, Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Author: L. S. Chumley
    Notes: n.d. 40 pp.
  - Item 3: The Crime of Centralia, Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Author: W. F. Dunn
    Notes: n.d. 16 pp.
  - Item 4: The I.W.W. in Theory and Practice, Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Author: Justus Ebert
    Notes: 3rd edition 124 pp.
  - Item 5: Industrial Unionism: The Road to Freedom, Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Author: Joseph J. Ettor
    Notes: 32 pp.
  - Item 6: California the Beautiful and Damned, Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Author: General Defense Committee
    Notes: 31 pp.
  - Item 7: Medieval California: Land of Orange Groves and Jails, Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Notes: 8 pp.
  - Item 8: The I.W.W. Reply to the Bed Trade Union International, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Author: General Executive Board
  - Item 9: The Onward Sweep of the Machine Process, Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Author: Nils H. Hanson; T. Glynn; Barbara L. y Frankenthal
    Notes: Includes Industrial Efficiency and Its Antidote by T. Glynn and The Diesel Motor by Barbara L. y Frankenthal.
  - Item 10: The General Strike., 1911; Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Author: William D. Haywood
    Notes: Includes "The Last War" by G. B. 18 and 23 pages.
  - Item 11: The Revolutionary I.W.W., 1916; Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Author: Grover H. Perry; B. H. Williams
- Industrial Workers of the World Publications 3, Publication (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Proletarian and Petit-Bourgeois, Publication (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Author: Austin Lewis; Charles Edward Russell; Scott Nearing
    Notes: Includes What Comes of Playing the Game by Charles Edward Russell and Those Who Own and Those Who Work by Scott Nearing
  - Item 2: Opening Statement of Geo. F. Vanderveer, Counsel for the Defense, of one hundred and one members of the Industrial Workers of the World, in the case of the U.S.A. vs. Wm. D. Haywood, et. al., 1918; Publication (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Author: George F. Vanderveer
    Notes: 102 pp.
  - Item 3: The Advancing Proletariat: A Study of the Movement of the Working Class from Wage Slavery to Freedom, 1917; Publication (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Author: Abner E. Woodruff
  - Item 4: The Evolution of Industrial Democracy, Publication (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Notes: 45 pp.
  - Item 5: Strajk Generalmy, 1911; Publication (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Author: William D. Haywood; Joseph J. Ettor; B. Schrager
    Notes: Polish edition of "The General Strike". 20 pp.
    Language: Polish.
  - Item 6: Esipuhe Ja Perustuslaki, Publication (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Author: Industrial Workers of the World (IWW): Soviet Union
    Notes: Finnish edtion of "Foreword and Constitution". 35 pp.
    Language: Finnish.
  - Item 7: Vallen-Kumouksellinen I.W.W., Publication (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Author: Grover H. Perry; K. Kiikka
    Notes: Finnish edition of "The Revolutionary I.W.W.". 47 pp.
  - Item 8: Az I.W.W.: Tortenete, Szerkezete Es Harcmodora, Publication (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Notes: Hungarian edtion of "The I.W.W.; Its History, Structure and Methods". 19pp.
    Language: Hungarian.
- Industrial Workers of the World Publications 4, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Revolutionary Writings: Poems and Prose, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Author: James Kelly Cole
    Notes: 85 pp.
  - Item 2: The Philadelphia Controversy, 1920; Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Author: R. F. Doree; Walter T. Nef
    Notes: 30 pp.
  - Item 3: The Immediate Demands of the I.W.W.: The Spirit of the Times, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Notes: 15 pp.
  - Item 4: I.W.W.: One Big Union of All Workers, The Greatest Thing on Earth, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Item 5: One Big Union of the I.W.W., Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Notes: 26 pp.
  - Item 6: An Open Letter To President Harding From 52 Members of the I.W.W. In Leavenworth Penitentiary Who Refuse to Apply for Individual Clemency, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Notes: 27 pp.
  - Item 7: Shall Freedom Die?: 166 Men In Jail For Labor. (By One of Them), Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Notes: 23 pp.
  - Item 8: War and The Workers, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Author: Walker C. Smith
  - Item 9: The Silent Defense: A Story of the Remarkable Trial of Members of the Industrial Workers of the World Held at Sacramento, California, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Author: Jean Sterling
    Notes: n.d. 47 pp.
  - Item 10: The Boycott Is Our Only Weapon Against Nazi Germany, 1933; Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Author: Samuel Untermyer
    Notes: 43 pp.
  - Item 11: Industrial Comnunism- The I.W.W., Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Author: Harold Lord Varney
    Notes: 24 pp.
  - Item 12: The First Congress of the Red Trade Union International at Moscow, 1921, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Author: George Williams
    Notes: 60 pp. (2nd revised ed.)
- Miscellaneous Pamphlets, Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: The Russian Famine - Pictures, Appeals, Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Author: Friends of Soviet Russia
    Notes: Russian Famine Pamphlet No. 1. 32 pp.
  - Item 2: The Right to Be Lazy and Other Stories, Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Author: Paul LaFargue; Charles H. Kerr
    Notes: Translated by Charles H. Kerr. 62 pp.
  - Item 3: Open The Factories, Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Author: Mary E. Marcy
  - Item 4: One Big Union of the Wage Workers Preamble and Constitution, Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Author: One Big Union of the Wage Workers
  - Item 5: American Deportation And Exclusion Laws, 1919; Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Author: Charles Recht
    Notes: 33 PP.
  - Item 6: Resolutions offered by Mr. F. C. Sibley of Franklin, Pennsylvania, and unanimously adopted at the annual meeting of Stockholders, April 18, 1921, with the recommendation that they be sent to all Stockholders, Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Author: F. C. Sibley
  - Item 7: Class Struggles in America., 1906; Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Author: A. M. Simons
    Notes: 64 pp.
  - Item 8: The United States To-Day! Program of the Workers Party of America, Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Author: Workers Party of America
- Bulletin Publishing Company. Butte, Montana., Publication (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: British Rule in India, Publication (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Author: William Jennings Bryan
    Notes: 13 pp.
  - Item 2: The Crime of Centralia, Publication (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Author: William F. Dunn
    Notes: 16 pp.
  - Item 3: Speech Delivered At Union Hall, Missoula, Montana, Sunday Evening, Nov. 16, 1919, Publication (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Notes: Editor of the Butte Daily Bulletin and Representative In the Legislature from Silver Bow County, Butte, Montana. 30 pp.
- National Non-Partisan League, Publication (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: General Rules and Some excuses For Not Joining the Non-Partisan League, Publication (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Author: National Nonpartisan League
    Notes: 19 pp.
  - Item 2: Origin, Purpose and Method of Operation: War Program and Statement of Principles, Publication (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Item 3: Program And Platform of Producers Political Alliance, Publication (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Author: National Nonpartisan League of Montana
  - Item 4: Resolutions Adopted try the Nonpartisan League Conference Held At St. Paul, Sept. 18-19-20, 1917, Publication (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Notes: 7 pp.
  - Item 5: Address of A. C. Townley President of the National Non-Partisan League At the Farmers and Workers Conference held at St. Paul, Sept. 18, 19, and 20, 1917, Publication (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Author: A. C. Townley
    Notes: 39 pp.
- One Big Union, Publication (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Socialist Party of the United States, Publication (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Is Socialism Inevitable? An Explanation of the Forces of Social Progress, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Author: August Claessens
  - Item 2: Labor And The Next War: A Study of American Imperialism And Its Effect Upon The Workers, Publication (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Author: James Oneal
  - Item 3: Starve The War And Feed America, Publication (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Author: National Campaign Committee
- The Church and Industrial Reconstruction, Publication (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: The Church and Industrial Reconstruction, 1921; Publication (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Author: William Adams Brown
    Notes: 296 pp
- The Soldier - Worker, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 16)
  January-July 1922
  - Item 1: The Soldier Worker, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Author: The Soldier Worker
    Notes: v.1:no.1 (1922:Jan.)
  - Item 2: The Soldier Worker, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Notes: v.1:no.2 (1922:Feb.)
  - Item 3: The Soldier Worker, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Notes: v.1:no.3 (1922:Mar.) There are two different issues with this enumeration and date.
  - Item 4: The Soldier Worker, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Item 5: The Soldier Worker, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Notes: v.1:no.4 (1922:Apr.)
  - Item 6: The Soldier Worker, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Notes: v.1:no.5 (1922:May)
  - Item 7: The Soldier Worker, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Notes: v.1:no.6 (1922:June)
  - Item 8: The Soldier Worker, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Notes: v.1:no.7 (1922:July)
- Harlow Pease Personal Papers, 1918-1922 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Stutz, R.L., Publication (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: The Attempted Secession of the Ansonia Workers Union Local 445 From The International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, CIO, 1948; Publication (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Author: R. L. Stutz
    Notes: January 16, 1948. Term paper for course ILR43.
- The New Unionism, Publication (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: The New Unionism, 1913; Publication (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Author: Andre Tridon
    Notes: 194+ pp.
- Montana Supreme Court, 1923; Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: John McCarthy, plaintiff and appellant, vs. Anaconda Copper Mining Company defendant and respondent. Transcript On Appeal in the Supreme Court of the State of Montana, 1923; Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Author: Supreme Court of the State of Montana
    Notes: 373 pp.
- Subversive Activities Control Board, 1962; Publication (Box 5, Folder 21)
  May 4, 1962. Bound Volume
  - Item 1: Report and Order of the Board in Robert F. Kennedy, Attorney General of the United States, Petitioner v. International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, respondent., 1962; Publication (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Author: Subversive Activities Control Board
    Notes: Docket no.116-56. Issued May 4, 1962
- Bingham Bulletin - 6/14/07 (Utah), Publication (Box 6)